<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<results>
	<page pageNumber="1">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2019—2024 STR ATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 1	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="2">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="3">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[World Food Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Strategic Plan 2019-2024 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Our Mission ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center mobilizes the resources of UC Davis to promote innovative, sustainable and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[equitable food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Our Vision ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis is recognized as the global hub for innovative solutions to meet the challenge of providing safe, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[nutritious and affordable food for all. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Our Plan ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Ranked first in the nation in agriculture and veterinary science, the breadth, depth and quality of UC Davis’ ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[faculty, research and educational programs in food systems and its many related areas is extraordinary. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis is recognized as a world leader in addressing the grand challenges facing global food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis’ strategic plan, To Boldly Go, expressly endorses the World Food Center as the key to connecting ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the university’s clusters of research excellence with industry, consumers, and public and philanthropic ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[entities to promote innovative, sustainable and equitable food systems. Similarly, the strategic plan of the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[College of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences lists advancing sustainable agriculture and food systems ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[as one of its four priority themes. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center has developed an ambitious five-year plan with three strategic priorities to fulfill its ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[vision of extending UC Davis’ global leadership in food systems solutions: ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will CONVENE UC Davis stakeholders working in food systems to ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[advance interdisciplinary collaboration. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis is home to over 60 centers and institutes and more than 400 faculty working across the university ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[in food systems. The World Food Center will bring these researchers together to synergize interdisciplinary ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[research and extension teams and magnify their effectiveness. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will CONNECT UC Davis experts in global food systems to external ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[partners to facilitate research opportunities and foster partnerships. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will actively develop relationships with industry, government, academic, and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[public/private organizations to promote UC Davis’ expertise in food systems and build mutually beneficial ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[partnerships for research, outreach, and education. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will COMMUNICATE the innovations and accomplishments of ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis centers, institutes, and scholars to amplify their contributions to improving global ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will promote UC Davis as the preeminent authority and resource for cutting-edge ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[innovations and solutions to grand challenges in food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 1	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="4">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Background ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Ranked 1st nationally ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[in agriculture ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis is ranked first in the nation in agriculture and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[veterinary science. The breadth, depth and quality of the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[university’s faculty, research and educational programs in ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food systems and its many related areas is long-standing ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and indisputable. UC Davis’ strategic plan, To Boldly ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Go, acknowledges this strength as a significant asset on ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[which the university must build to advance its important ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[agenda “to enable and support research… that matters ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[across and between the disciplines, in support of a ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[healthy planet and the physical and societal well-being of ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[its inhabitants.” ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The UC Davis World Food Center was established in ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2013 by the Office of the Chancellor and is now housed ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[within the College of Agricultural and Environmental ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Sciences, working with constituencies across the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[university and beyond. The center is part of the College’s ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Global Engagement pillar and operates under the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[leadership of an Associate Dean. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[1st in the world for ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[veterinary medicine ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center mobilizes the resources of UC ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Davis to promote innovative, sustainable and equitable ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food systems and serves as a portal to the talent and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[expertise within the university. The World Food Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[works in tandem with researchers from UC Davis and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[other academic institutions, public sector officials, civic ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[organizations and private industry partners to develop ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[innovative solutions for challenges facing local and global ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[To Boldly Go expressly endorses the World Food Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[as an important vehicle to coordinate UC Davis’ strength in global food systems and “mobilize ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the research, educational and outreach resources in partnership with consumers, public and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[philanthropic entities, and agricultural, marine and food industries, to promote innovative, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[sustainable and equitable food systems.” To Boldly Go also envisions that the coordination of ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[interdisciplinary clusters of research excellence through the World Food Center will increase ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the visibility of UC Davis’ broad expertise in food systems and related topics, while providing ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[access to larger-scale funding opportunities requiring interdisciplinary solutions. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center strategic plan also builds on the Core Priority Themes described ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[in the current College of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences’ Strategic Plan (2015- ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2020), contributing in particular to the Sustainable Agriculture and Food Systems theme. As ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[noted there, “sustainable agriculture and food systems ensure secure, safe, and high quality ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[healthful food for the world’s population without negative social and environmental impacts. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="5">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[… Sustainable agriculture and food systems are fundamental to all aspects of human existence, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[requiring significant investment in existing strengths and integrated growth opportunities.” ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will also support other Core Priority Themes by promoting better ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[nutrition and health, enabling viable agriculture/landscape/urban ecosystems and meeting the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[challenges of climate change. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center Strategic Plan translates these broad goals into three major strategic ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[priorities and concrete, measurable initiatives to achieve them over the next five years. The ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[plan articulates a vision of the World Food Center as a forum to: (1) convene the many centers, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[institutes and faculty working in the areas broadly defined as food systems; (2) connect ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[internal and external actors in constructive networking and develop partnerships with industry, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[government and public/private organizations; and (3) communicate the innovations and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[accomplishments of UC Davis centers, institutes, and scholars to amplify their contributions to ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[research and extension in global food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 3	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="6">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[4 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="7">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The Global Challenge and the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis Food Landscape ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Challenges to producing sufficient, safe and nutritious ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food are increasing: population growth, climate change, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[resource scarcity and environmental degradation are ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[threats to economically viable food systems worldwide. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Global population has increased from 3 billion in 1960 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[to 7.6 billion today and is anticipated to plateau at nearly ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[10 billion by 2050. Increased productivity and efficiency ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[gains after 1960 enabled global food production to keep ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[pace with population growth with limited expansion of ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the environmental footprint of agriculture until recently. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[However, these methods were not adopted uniformly ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[around the world. Most of the next 2 billion people will ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[be born in Africa, where current agricultural yields are ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[about 20% of what could be possible. Expanding the area ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[of land utilized for food production is not a desirable ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[option, as it releases massive amounts of carbon into the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[atmosphere, exacerbating climate change and destructive ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[weather events that are threatening current food ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[production systems. In addition, as the most productive ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[lands are already utilized for food production, expansion ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[of agriculture will be on marginally productive lands, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[resulting in diminishing crop yields while accelerating ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[deforestation, erosion and greenhouse gas emissions. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Thus, applying science and technology to sustainably ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[intensify food production on existing agricultural lands is ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the overriding challenge for global agricultural systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[California is an excellent location for research on ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[improving efficiency, productivity and sustainability of ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food systems due to the abundance and diversity of its ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[agricultural output, its emphasis on the importance of ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[human and animal health and nutrition, and its active ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[strategies to prevent and mitigate the environmental and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[economic threats to sustaining food production. This ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[nexus among food, environment and health inspires ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[research and extension work in food systems across ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Global population has ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[increased from 3 billion ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[in 1960 to 7.6 bilion ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[today and is anticipated ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[to plateau at nearly ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[10 bilion by 2050. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[California is an excellent ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[location for research on ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[improving efficiency, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[productivity and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[sustainanility of ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 5	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="8">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The Food Landscape at UC Davis ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[60+ centers and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[institutes working in ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food systems ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis is recognized globally for its leadership in agriculture and food systems research, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[extension and outreach. In addition to the College of Agricultural and Environmental ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Sciences, the university has extensive food-related academic resources in the College of ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Biological Sciences, the College of Engineering, the College of Letters and Science, the School ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[of Veterinary Medicine, and the School of Medicine. These programs offer undergraduate, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[graduate and professional degree curricula, conduct research, and deliver extension and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[outreach initiatives. UC Davis is home to more than 60 centers, institutes and programs ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[outside of the formal academic structure that provide expertise and resources targeted toward ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[specific aspects of food systems. Many of these are interdisciplinary and collectively address a ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[broad range of topics in food production, delivery, consumption, health and public policy. The ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[overriding goal of the World Food Center is to synergize and focus the unparalleled resources ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[of UC Davis to address the most important challenges facing the future of human society. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center developed this diagram of the UC Davis food landscape to illustrate ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the breadth of programs serving the needs of regional, national and global food systems. The ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[focus is primarily on the College of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences, but food-related ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[programs span the entire campus. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[350+ agricultural ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[scholars 6 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="9">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[FOOD LANDSCAPE FIGURE ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Food Systems ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[C B ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[3 25 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[56 M ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[34 35 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[42 59 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[A 1 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Health 	DEPARTMENTS ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 A 	 Agricultural and Resource Economics ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 B 	 Animal Science	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 C 	 Biological and Agricultural Engineering	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 D 	 Entomology and Nematology	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 E 	 Environmental Science and Policy	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 F 	 Environmental Toxicology	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 G 	 Food Science and Technology	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 H	 Human Ecology	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 I 	 Land, Air and Water Resources	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	J	 Nutrition	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 K	 Plant Pathology	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 L	 Plant Sciences	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 M	 Viticulture and Enology	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 N	 Wildlife, Fish, and Conservation Biology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[CENTERS AND INSTITUTES ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 1	 Agricultural Sustainability Institute ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 2	 Agricultural Issues Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 3	 Agronomy Research and Information Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 4	 Air Quality Research Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 5	 Arboretum and Public Garden ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 6	 Blum Center for Developing Economics ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 7	 Bodega Marine Laboratory ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 8	 California Animal Health and Food Safety 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Laboratory ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 9	 California Center for Urban Horticulture ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 10	 California Crop Improvement Association ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 11	 California Institute of Food and Agriculture 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Research ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[58 6 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[7 17 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[18 20 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[L 4 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[12 15 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[19 21 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[36 37 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[39 44 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[55 54 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[16 H ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[E 22 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[26 38 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[28 I ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[N 40 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[43 51 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[60 45 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[48 53 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2 F ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[46 41 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[57 33 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[27 31 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[8 23 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[14 24 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[10 52 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[50 11 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[13 G ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[30 49 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[K 9 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[5 25 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[47 D ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[25 J ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 16 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[department domestic ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[international Policy ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 12	 Center for Animal and Disease Modeling and 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 Surveillance ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 13	 Center for Aquatic Biology and Aquaculture ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 14	 Center for Food Animal Health ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 15	 Center for Regional Change ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 16	 Center for Spatial Sciences ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 17	 Center for Spatial Technologies and Remote 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Sensing ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 18	 Center for Water-Energy Efficiency ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 19	 Center for Watershed Sciences ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 20	 Child Family Institute for Innovation and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Entrepreneurship ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 21	 Chile Life Sciences Innovation Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 22	 Coastal and Marine Sciences Institute ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 23	 Coffee Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 24	 Conservation Agriculture Systems Innovation 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 25	 Dairy Research and Information Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 26	 Energy and Efficiency Institute ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 27	 Foods for Health Institute ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 28	 Food Loss and Waste Collaborative ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 29	 Foundation Plant Services ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 30	 Fruit and Nut Research and Information Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 31	 Genome Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 32	 Gifford Center for Population Studies ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 33	 Global Healthshare Initiative ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 34	 Honey and Pollination Center at the RMI ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 35	 Innovation Institute for Food and Health ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 36	 Institute for Food and Agricultural Literacy ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 37	 International Programs Office ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 38	 John Muir Institute of the Environment ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 39	 Olive Center at the RMI ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 40	 Public Intellectual Property Resource for 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Agriculture ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 41	 Plant Breeding Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 42	 Postharvest Technology Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 43	 Program for International Energy Technologies ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 44	 Program in International and Community 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Nutrition ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 45	 Robert Mondavi Institute for Wine and Food 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Science ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 46	 Seed Biotechnology Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 47	 Smart Farm ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 48	 UC CalFresh Nutrition Education Program ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 49	 UC Nursery and Floriculture Alliance ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 50	 UC Rangelands ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 51	 USAID-FTF Innovation Lab-Assets and Market 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Access ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 52	 USAID-FTF Innovation Lab-Climate Resilient 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Chickpea ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 53	 USAID-FTF Innovation Lab-Climate Resilient 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Millet ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 54	 USAID-FTF Innovation Lab Genomics to 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 Improve Poultry ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 55	 USAID-FTF Innovation Lab Horticulture ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 56	 USAID-FTF Innovation Lab Sustainable ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Intensification ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 57	 Vegetable Research and Information Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 58	 Weed Research and Information Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 59	 Western Center for Agricultural Health and 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[			 Safety ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 60	 Western Institute for Food Safety and Security ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 7	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="10">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[MISSION AND VISION ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Our Mission ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center mobilizes ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the resources of UC Davis to ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[promote innovative, sustainable ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and equitable food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Our Vision ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis is recognized as the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[global hub for innovative solutions ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[to meet the challenge of providing ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[safe, nutritious and affordable food ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[for all. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[8 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="11">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 9	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="12">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Strategic Priorities ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Strategic Priority I: ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will CONVENE UC Davis stakeholders working in food ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[systems to advance interdisciplinary collaboration. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Leveraging the expertise of food systems ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[scholars across UC Davis and the UC System to ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[mobilize interdisciplinary teams and compete ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[for large-scale funding opportunities requires ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[higher levels of collaboration and coordination ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[within the university. By providing forums, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[facilitating collaborations and fostering ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[connections for interdisciplinary work, the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[World Food Center amplifies the collective ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[resources of UC Davis’ centers, institutes and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[faculty. The center serves as a liaison with ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis units involved with grant-seeking ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and fundraising efforts, such as the Offices ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[of Research, Government and Community ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Relations, and Development and Alumni ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Relations. An ongoing dialogue among these ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[relevant university units will keep all apprised of opportunities and engaged in tandem to seek ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[project and research funding proactively. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Recognizing that large-scale food and agricultural research is specialized and evolving, the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[World Food Center will establish its presence among public and private funders to advocate for ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis’ expertise and facilitate successful procurement of grants for food systems research. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The center will foster interdisciplinary cooperation to seek new funding opportunities and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[work in collaboration with services offered by the Office of Research and other development ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[resources to achieve these goals. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[1. The World Food Center will provide ongoing opportunities to convene ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[stakeholders from centers and institutes, researchers, and extension specialists ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[across all UC Davis schools, colleges and units working in food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 a. 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Map the expertise in food systems across UC Davis, broadening the scope 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[as needed to present a complete picture for university and external audiences. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[This data will contribute to interactive electronic resources currently under 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[development in several university units, including the College of Agricultural ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and Environmental Sciences, Global Affairs and the University Library. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 b. 	 Foster interdisciplinary academic and extension collaboration by providing 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 seed funding for workshops, forums, and symposia that bring subject-matter 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 experts together via the Aligning the Food System platform. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 c. 	 Build upon the popular Food for Thought Showcases and other networking 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 events as venues for food-focused centers, institutes and faculty at UC Davis 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 to present their work to the academic and industry food community. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 d. 	 Convene interdisciplinary campus stakeholders in value-added networking 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 events on a quarterly basis to share developments and opportunities for 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 collaboration, particularly among new and junior faculty. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[10 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="13">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 e.	 Support opportunities for students and faculty to interact with the foremost 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 agricultural institutions around the world by leading UC Davis’ involvement 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 with the A5 Consortium. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2. The World Food Center will strengthen UC Davis’ ability to compete for ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[large-scale, cross-functional food system projects by serving as an institutional ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[resource on funding opportunities and proposal development. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 a.	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 Coordinate efforts with UC Davis experts and other campus resources, such 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[as the Offices of Research, Government and Community Relations and other ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[university and UC system initiatives to identify opportunities and disseminate 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[information about large-scale interdisciplinary projects. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 b.	 Identify the areas in which large projects are being funded and assemble 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 interdisciplinary teams in anticipation of requests for proposals to ensure that 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 UC Davis is prepared to act quickly on funding opportunities as they arise. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 c.	 Supplement the services offered to potential grantees by the Office of Research 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 by creating a staff position to offer specialized expertise and support to faculty 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 developing large interdisciplinary grant proposals in food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 d.	 Host quarterly conference calls for World Food Center stakeholders with the 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 Office of Research and similar units on grant opportunities in food systems, 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 including funding trends, upcoming projects and related matters. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 e.	 Offer specialized expertise and guidance on the development and coordination 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 of international grant proposals in food systems, supported by the College of 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 Agricultural and Environmental Sciences Global Engagement office. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 f.	 Liaise with university and system-wide programs relevant to food systems, 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 including the Big Idea initiatives, One Climate, and One Health to promote ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 UC Davis expertise and keep scholars appraised of new initiatives in these fields. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 g.	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 Inform and influence public policy by coalescing UC Davis experts in food systems 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[to develop science-based policy briefs that align with the efforts of the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis Office of Government and Community Relations and the University of 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[California Government Relations teams. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 h.	 Offer UC Davis’ expertise in food systems to state and national agencies that 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		 are developing research funding priorities. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 11	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="14">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[12 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="15">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[3. The World Food Center will establish an advisory council composed of ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[informed and well-positioned leaders and experts to ensure that the center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[remains at the forefront of developments in food and agricultural science, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[research and extension. Potential members of this board include: ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 a.	 Faculty and administrators from UC Davis and the University of California system, 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 as well as other leading academic institutions ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 b.	 Local, state and national government agencies ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 c.	 Foundations and non-governmental organizations ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 d.	 Leaders in the food and agricultural industries ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 e.	 Consumer and health organizations ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Strategic Priority II: ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will CONNECT UC Davis experts in global food systems ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[to external partners to facilitate research opportunities and foster partnerships. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[To Boldly Go envisions a future where dialogue across the disciplines provides the foundation ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[for interdisciplinary solutions to grand challenges facing global food systems. Ensuring that ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the collective expertise available at UC Davis is frequently and effectively utilized requires the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[mobilization of collaborative partnerships between university units and external organizations, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[including government agencies, industry, foundations, funders, and national and international ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[research institutions. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will work to elevate UC Davis’ recognition as a world leader for ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food systems research and practice. The center will cultivate relationships with external ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[organizations in the public/private sectors that have the potential to partner with UC Davis on ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[research and problem-solving initiatives in food systems and connect them to campus experts ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and research units. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[1. The World Food Center will systematically and proactively cultivate ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[relationships with funders and collaborators to propel UC Davis’ position ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[as the premier institution for interdisciplinary research solutions and as a ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[global leader in food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 a. 	Build relationships with foundations and companies in the food and 				 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 agriculture industries with funding and research priorities that overlap with 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 campus expertise. Proactively influence grant-making priorities using policy 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 briefs and research reports to position UC Davis as a leading contender for 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 funding and project leadership opportunities. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 b.	 Establish ongoing relationships with scientific councils, policy groups, think 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 tanks, and similar organizations to promote emerging research and innovation 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 in the food and agriculture space. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 c.	 Promote UC Davis at major conferences and events around the world to 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 raise the profile of the university, make connections with potential partners 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 and collaborators, and stay abreast of current initiatives and emerging research 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 in the field. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 d.	 Serve as a portal to connect external stakeholders with expertise at UC Davis. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 e.	 Enlist UC Davis experts to represent the university around the country and the 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 world as advocates for cutting-edge food systems research and solutions. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 13	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="16">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[f.	 Partner with Global Affairs and its Global Centers program as well as other 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 international initiatives to expand the global reach and reputation of UC Davis 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 in food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 g.	 Leverage existing campus resources, including the Offices of Research, 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 Development and Alumni Relations, and Government Relations and 				 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 Community Engagement, to identify potential funders and collaborators ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 in all sectors. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 h.	 Develop a comprehensive outreach plan and communications materials that 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 showcase campus resources to inform and cultivate relationships with 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 potential partners. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2. The World Food Center will collaborate with external and internal ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[stakeholders to identify grand challenges and targeted priorities in global food ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[systems that coalesce centers, institutes, and departments around large-scale, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[interdisciplinary and multi-institutional projects. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 a.	 Invite extramural stakeholders and potential public/private partners 				 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 to UC Davis on a regular basis to meet with experts and attend events that 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 showcase UC Davis’ expertise and achievements. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 b.	 Share the resources and contacts relating to extramural partnerships and funding 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 developed by the World Food Center with UC Davis stakeholders. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 c.	 Map UC Davis expertise in food systems to the United Nations Sustainable 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 Development Goals and other regional, national, and international priorities to 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 facilitate connections to external opportunities coalescing around those goals. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 d.	 Evaluate and replicate models and best practices of successful global research 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 institutes. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Strategic Priority III: ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will communicate the innovations and accomplishments ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[of UC Davis centers, institutes, and scholars to amplify their contributions to ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[improving global food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[In tandem with university communications teams, the World Food Center will elevate and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[amplify the accomplishments of UC Davis centers, institutes and scholars working to improve ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[food systems. UC Davis is globally acknowledged as an academic powerhouse in food systems, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and broadening its commitment to communicating new research and problem-solving ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[strategies through the World Food Center will enhance the university’s visibility and draw new ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[audiences into this work. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[The World Food Center will build its own communications infrastructure to provide direct ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[support to the more than 60 centers and institutes focused on food systems through messaging ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[campaigns, interactive journalism, and digital media. The center will also focus on building ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[cooperative relationships with university and college communications units to enhance their ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[efforts and develop cohesive strategies to provide new avenues to magnify the innovations and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[accomplishments in food systems across UC Davis. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[14 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="17">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 15	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="18">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[16 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="19">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[1. The World Food Center will appoint a communications specialist to ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[oversee the development and implementation of a messaging strategy and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[comprehensive communications plan that raises awareness of UC Davis ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[expertise and resources in food systems to internal and external audiences. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 a.	 Establish collaborative and mutually reinforcing relationships with the UC Davis and 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 UC offices responsible for communication, including the College of Agricultural and 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 Environmental Sciences, UC Davis Strategic Communications, UC system campuses, 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 and the Office of the President. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 b.	 Fill a communications niche at UC Davis by sharing messaging that identifies 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 and works toward solving grand challenges in global food systems using 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 innovative, interdisciplinary solutions. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 c.	 Emphasize UC Davis’ role as the premier agricultural school in the nation and 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 as a key problem-solver for the threats facing global food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 d.	 Promote UC Davis as the hub for experts and innovators working in global 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 e.	 Develop the World Food Center’s communications strategy with messaging ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 focused around global food systems as a whole to bring the many threads of 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 UC Davis food and agricultural research together. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[		f.	 Establish and build upon the World Food Center’s online presence using various 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 tools, including social media and search engine optimization 	strategies. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2. In partnership with the College of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences’ ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Office of Communications, support UC Davis faculty, centers, and institutes in ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the food and agriculture space by magnifying their visibility and impact through ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[communications strategies. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 a.	 Partner with UC Davis centers and institutes to identify new accomplishments and 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 research breakthroughs for coverage in communications campaigns. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 b.	 Provide direct support to centers, institutes and faculty seeking messaging 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 amplification via the World Food Center’s communications platforms. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 c.	 Offer coverage recommendations to UC Davis communications units and 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 media outlets focused on the success of university experts in food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 d.	 Provide technical support and visibility for webinars and other vehicles enabling ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[				 UC Davis researchers to amplify their messaging to broader audiences. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 17	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="20">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Metrics for Measuring Success ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[To measure the outcomes of this strategic plan, the World Food ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Center will monitor and evaluate the following metrics: ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[1. Audience engagement. The World Food Center will measure ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the levels of engagement with audiences at its events via surveys ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and feedback requests. Further metrics will include attendee turn- ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[out and participants’ expertise, areas of research, etc., relevant to ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[the goals of the specific event. The World Food Center will also ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[analyze the representation of experts visiting UC Davis for these ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[engagements and evaluate its success in fostering diversity and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[inclusion in its audiences. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[2. Research and funding outcomes. The number of submitted ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[proposals and amount of funding received from the World Food ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Center’s efforts to convene interdisciplinary teams to apply for ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[large-scale grant awards and project opportunities will serve as key ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[metrics. The size and scope of these projects will document the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[World Food Center’s success in gaining new funding sources for ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[3. Outreach and community engagement. As the World Food ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Center engages with the local, regional, and national communities ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and media outlets in food systems, we will tally UC Davis’ ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[representation on relevant science and policy boards, councils, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[organizations, etc. Outcomes of digital communications will be ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[assessed via analysis of data from the World Food Center’s website ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and social media. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[4. Stakeholder relationships. The World Food Center will catalog ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[its relationships with relevant contacts at the major foundations, ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[companies, government agencies, and universities in the food and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[agriculture space in a database that will be available to other ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[UC Davis units. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[18 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="21">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 19	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="22">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[VI.	 The Strategic Planning Process ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[To Boldly Go embraces the World Food Center as an important vehicle for implementing ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[university-wide goals of tapping into the depth of food and agriculture scholarship and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[extension, developing partnerships in research and innovation, and raising the visibility of the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[university’s expertise and resources in food systems. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Upon the World Food Center’s transition to the College of Agricultural and Environmental ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Sciences, a new framework for activities was developed by a faculty visioning committee and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[launched in 2017 under the leadership of an interim director. This strategy was implemented ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[by refocusing the mission of the World Food Center and establishing a series of successful pilot ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[programs to foster university-wide interdisciplinary engagement. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Development of this strategic plan started in February 2018 by interviewing UC Davis faculty ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[members and regional industry and community leaders to discuss how the World Food Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[could support their goals. In January 2019, the College of Agricultural and Environmental ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Sciences appointed an Associate Dean of Global Engagement to direct the World Food Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[and the College’s international programs. The Associate Dean, in collaboration with the ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Steering Committee for the 2019 strategic planning process, has worked diligently to translate ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[these recommendations into an ambitious program with three main goals to be accomplished ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[with concrete, measurable steps. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[20 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="23">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Strategic Planning Participants ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[This strategic plan incorporates extensive consultation with over 100 UC Davis leaders, including department heads, center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[directors, and other faculty and staff over the course of two years. Below is a listing of many individuals and groups that ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[contributed to the strategic plan writing process and developed the consensus of the goals defined within it. The World Food ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[Center thanks them and others who may not be listed for their opinions and advice throughout this process. ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[LEADERSHIP AND STAFF ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Ermias Kebreab, Associate Dean of Global 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 Engagement and Director of the World Food Center, 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 College of Agricultural & Environmental Sciences ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Kent Bradford, Associate Director and ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 former Interim Director, World Food Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Kaylee D’Amico, Program Manager, World Food Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLANNING CONSULTANTS ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Adelaide Ferguson ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Rachael LeMasters ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[VISIONING AND IMPLEMENTATION COMMITTEE ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Timothy Beatty, Agricultural and Resource Economics ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Catherine Brinkley, Human Ecology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Joanna Chiu, Entomology and Nematology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Kay Dewey, Nutrition ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Robert Hijmans, Environmental Science and Policy ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Juan Medrano, Animal Science ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Elizabeth Mitcham, Plant Sciences ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• James Sanchirico, Environmental Science and Policy ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• David Campbell, College of Agricultural and 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 Environmental Sciences ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLANNING CONTRIBUTORS ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Robert Atwill, School of Veterinary Medicine ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Lars Berglund, School of Medicine ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Michael Carter, Agricultural and Resource Economics ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Doug Cook, Plant Pathology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Cristina Davis, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Paul Dodd, Office of Research ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Dan Flynn, College of Agricultural and Environmental 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	Sciences • Nann Fangue, Wildlife, Fish, and Conservation Biology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Bruce German, Food Science and Technology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Angela Haczku, School of Medicine ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Andrew Hargadon, Graduate School of Management ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Amina Harris, Honey and Pollination Center ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Linda Harris, Food Science and Technology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Ken Hiatt, City of Woodland ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• William Horwath, Land, Air and Water Resources ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Benjamin Houlton, Land, Air and Water Resources ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Mary Kimball, Center for Land-Based Learning ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Francois Korn, Seed Central ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• William Lacy, Human Ecology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Beatriz Martinez Lopez, School of Veterinary Medicine ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Jonathan London, Human Ecology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Richard Michelmore, Molecular and Cellular Biology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Jeff Mitchell, Plant Sciences ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Alyson Mitchell, Food Science and Technology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• John Palmer, California Crop Improvement Association ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Stacey Parker, UC Davis Arboretum ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Dushyant Pathak, Office of Research ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Joanna Regulska, Global Affairs ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Robert Rice, Environmental Toxicology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Don Saylor, Yolo County Board of Supervisors ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Sharon Shoemaker, California Institute of Food and 		 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 Agricultural Research ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Justin Siegel, Chemistry ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Christopher Simmons, Food Science and Technology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Kamaljeet Singh-Khaira, UC CalFresh Nutrition 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 Education Program ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• David Slaughter, Biological and Agricultural Engineering ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Woutrina Smith, School of Veterinary Medicine ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Edward Spang, Food Science and Technology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Christine Stewart, Nutrition ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Dan Sumner, Agricultural and Resource Economics ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Ronald Tjeerdema, College of Agricultural and 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 Environmental Sciences ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Tom Tomich, Agricultural Sustainability Institute ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Andrew Waterhouse, Viticulture and Enology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Caren Weintraub, College of Agricultural and 			 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[	 Environmental Sciences ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Carl Winter, Food Science and Technology ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Theodore Wun, School of Medicine ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Florence Zakharov, Plant Sciences ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[• Huaijun Zhou, Animal Science ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[STRATEGIC PLAN 2019-2024 21	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
	<page pageNumber="24">
		<paragraph><![CDATA[worldfoodcenter.ucdavis.edu ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[22 UC DAVIS WORLD FOOD CENTER 	 ]]></paragraph>
		<paragraph><![CDATA[]]></paragraph>
	</page>
</results>